Welcome, welcome.
We're logging in early.
We are going to ensure that
the YouTube stream is working
Go.
Gotta make some updates to
the webinar stream on YouTube
Welcome, welcome.
Come on in.
Join us, join us, join us.
We're gonna get started
here in just a few minutes
I believe that's working.
Let me verify
Great
Hello, hello, Rachel.
Hello, Clara.
Hello, Anna, Sophie, Reese.
Good to see you guys
here in the chat already.
Let's see how we doing.
We got over 100 people here live already.
Amazing.
Good to see you guys.
And we're early.
We're three minutes
early, so it's just us.
Uh, let me know Yes, testing,
testing, testing, Jeff.
That's right.
That's what we're doing.
Um, let me know in the
chat how your day's going.
How we feeling?
Tuesday, glad it's not Monday
So we've got Stephanie from Texas.
We've got Catherine from Vancouver Island.
Atlanta, says Stacy Lynn
Overwhelmed, Sheila.
Okay, tell me why you're
overwhelmed, overwhelmed.
See if we can do something about that
Two days away from launching, Margaret.
Congrats
I feel that as well.
Oh man, we got people all over the world.
We got some late night, some,
some late work owls here.
I love that
Let's see.
Gotta put my presentation
thing up on the teleprompter.
We got Andrew from the Boston area.
We got folks in Amsterdam.
Sophie, we have two team
members here at Creator Science
who are in the Netherlands.
Crazy, crazy
Speaking of team members, I should
probably check our team Slack
and see if anything is broken
Mal says we're live.
My wife says we're live.
Good.
Uh, evident to me now, which is great.
Tubi in the house.
Yes.
We have our Creator Science
mascot, Tubey, who is also our AI
assistant here at Creator Science,
and we have our own plushie
And he sits here.
I don't know if you guys have ever heard
of the, uh, the rubber ducky theory.
I don't know if it's a theory
so much as like a process for
engineers who are debugging code.
The rubber ducky method is basically
when you're looking at code and
trying to understand what is broken,
you read through each line of code
and explain to a rubber duck on your
desk what that line of code does.
So sometimes my rubber duck method
is talking to Tubey and saying,
"Here's what I'm trying to do,"
especially liquid code in Kit.
It's like, "Here's what I'm trying
to do, and it's not quite working."
Uh, and then we walk through it.
Or I use my OpenClaw AI assistant,
Tubey, and he just solves
a problem for me sometimes.
Stacy Lynn wants a plushie.
Okay.
Stacy Lynn, if you can rally another like
299 people, then we will have enough votes
for a minimum order quantity of plushies
Little known fact, we have a completed
and functional Creator Science merch
store that we have simply not yet
published publicly for some of our
more popular, uh, hoodie designs
that I've been personally wearing.
This was a hoodie that we designed
for our, uh, in-person offline
event for lab members this
year, and Tubey is on the back.
We got Tubey on the back of this.
I wanna introduce him into our
YouTube content because, uh, I think
there's a lot of potential here.
I don't know if, if anyone here is
a fan of homestarrunner.com, like
millennial, uh, Flash video content
from early 2000s, but I have aspirations
of making our YouTube content feel a
little bit more like Homestar Runner
and Strong Bad Emails, and my friend
Tubi here would be a part of that
Okay, I see some Homestar fans
in the, in the audience here.
Love that.
Okay, great.
Thank you Dominique for validating me.
Uh, Trogdor.
Yes.
Uh, okay.
Little known fact because I see we have
some Homestar fans in the audience here.
My sister Emily had a Strong
Bad email that he answered,
and you can find it on YouTube.
If you watch the YouTube video,
uh, the email was called Marzipan.
So if you search Homestar Runner…
Actually, you probably search
Strong Bad Email Marzipan, you'll
get my sister's Strong Bad email.
Uh, it's written by Emily
C. from Ohio or Ohio
All right, we got Omir from Turkey.
I'm sorry if I didn't
pronounce that correctly
We got folks trickling in.
We love to see it.
I'm going to, uh, just hold
space for a couple more minutes
here as folks trickle in
Yes, Jason, those were real emails.
Those were real emails that
people sent and had answered
What's Homestar is a valid question.
Uh, you could, you could
just, uh, look that up.
It's kind of a trip down memory lane,
but if you don't remember it, it's
not much of a memory lane for you.
And I, uh, I don't know if now is
the time to get into Homestar Runner.
Unsure.
We got Maggie in the house.
We got Tommy in the house.
There's Laura in the Netherlands.
Brandon from Pittsburgh.
Caleb from Boise
Great.
Seeing multiple folks here from the lab.
Love to see that
I'm seeing a couple people
reporting looping of audio.
Is that more than just one person?
Let me know
Okay, why would that be happening?
Okay.
I'm not sure why it's
happening for some folks.
If it's happening for
you, I would consider just
refreshing and coming back in
Okay.
All right, guys.
Uh, well, excited to have you here.
We are gonna get started here in a moment.
I'm going to start sharing my screen
Here we are.
Welcome to the Membership
Summit, my friends.
I am so excited to have you here
So excited to have you with us.
Excited to dig into this
three-day event with you.
My team and I have been working super,
super hard on this, and I'm trying
to make it as, uh, valuable and, um,
contained yet thorough as possible.
So throughout this summit, I am going
to be answering questions that come
up in the chat if I can catch them.
Uh, I believe you can enter questions
specifically in the chat and mark them
as a question so that it goes into a
special questions queue on my side as the
presenter, and I will be able to, uh, come
back and answer those more specifically.
In the chat, we've already
done a lot of this.
I've, uh, been asking you
where you're calling in from.
We've seen a lot of this.
So why don't we go here?
Why don't you let me know why you
are here today, what you're hoping,
hoping to take away from this?
I would love to hear a
little bit about that.
I'm gonna read some of these out.
I'm gonna zoom in on the chat so I can
read it a little bit easier as well
France, Boston, Belgium, Maine
We've got Elle launching her women's
health community in September
Liz wants to make her membership better.
We got folks with high-ticket
programs, revamping an
existing membership structure.
Keely, good to see you.
I know we've interacted
in email a little bit.
Amy wants to increase her conversion.
Kyle wants to make his
membership as amazing as the Lab.
Thank you for that, uh, hidden compliment.
I just, I appreciate that.
Hey, Tom's in the house.
Tom is thinking about his next
steps for starting a community
Christian's looking for starting a good
membership program for self-paced learning
Great.
Great, great, great.
Matt says, "I think it's time to start
a membership." Nino in the house.
Nino, good to see you
All right cool.
Let's get started
My name is Jay.
I've been doing this
content thing since 2017.
Um, I spent a year leading community
at SPI, Smart Passive Income,
with Pat Flynn in 2021, and that
was actually after six months of
consulting in 2020, mid-pandemic.
That was crazy, but I helped them
launch SPI Pro in 2020, and that
was a really awesome experience.
It went so well that they asked me to
come in and lead community for them in
2021, which I was, uh, excited to do.
But my business kept growing, and in
2022, I went back out onto my own, started
building behind the Creator Science
brand, and launched my membership in 2022
The lab is a place that I've been running,
like I said, since twenty twenty-two.
It's where creators
experiment and learn together.
We started that in twenty twenty-two.
We're at about three hundred and forty
members across different tiers this year.
And in twenty twenty-five, we had our
biggest year, uh, of the membership in
terms of revenue, earning four hundred
and ninety-six thousand dollars.
Uh, on the right here, this
is a photo from our most
recent offline event in Boise.
This happened just this month.
Two weeks ago, we decided to take on
organizing an in-person offline event the
same month that we're doing this summit.
It's been an intense month, guys.
So as you're hanging with me over
the next couple of days, excited, uh,
to have you here, but also just know
that, um, team's been working hard.
We're trying to do our best for you.
If something breaks, if audio is
looping, hopefully we troubleshoot that
here live in real time, and we have,
have some grace for us here as well.
Today is all about teaching.
I've allocated ninety minutes
here, and if we go over a little
bit, we go over a little bit.
It's all good.
All I wanna do today is sit
here and teach what I can.
Um, if by the end of this week
you've enjoyed this experience and
you want some more help and support
working with me to help you get
started, you'll have, you'll have an
opportunity for that to happen as well.
But in the meantime, I'm gonna share
as much as I possibly can over these
next three days to give you a huge
leg up from where you're coming from.
You know, I know we're all
starting at different points.
We all have, uh, different goals.
But my goal is that you leave these
three days and you feel like I have so
much more to work from, and I can, uh,
skip over some of the issues that I
might have otherwise stumbled through.
That's my goal here
for the next three days
Also, I want you guys to say
hello to Anna here in the chat.
If you see Anna in the chat,
Anna is a member of my team,
and she is monitoring the chat.
She's helping me, uh, manage some things.
She is a part of the Career Science team.
She's my integrator, and if she, uh,
s- notices that I miss something,
then you can absolutely, uh,
know that she will be jumping in
Okay.
Real quick, I'd love to know which
one of these four options sounds
the most like you right now.
Uh, A, you're considering a membership.
B, you have no plans for a membership,
but you're here to learn anyway.
C, you have a membership, but
it's struggling a little bit.
And D, I have a membership or you have
a membership and it's doing great.
Which one sounds more like you?
See a lot of As, some Cs
I see a D and it's from Anna.
I hope she's talking about the lab.
A, C, lots of As and Cs.
Okay, great.
Joy, congrats.
Anyone who's answering D, I see you.
You're crushing it.
I hope there's something of value here
for you as well, but keep on keeping on.
Keep doing your thing
Great.
Great, great, great, great, great
So regardless, you're in the right place.
Um, like I said, if you answered D on
that, congrats, and feel free to share any
thoughts in the chat of what's going well
for you, because I think that's probably
something we can all learn from as well.
So we're about to start.
We've, we've seemingly
identified the looping issue.
It seems to be if you leave
the tab and come back.
So, uh, consider closing the other
tabs and just locking in with us here.
We're about to get much, much
more tactical than I've started.
Um, and I hope that, uh,
this is worth your time.
So here's how the next three days look.
Today we're talking about why memberships
in twenty twenty six, why, uh, this
is a great year to start a membership,
why, um, this is a big opportunity, I
believe, for creators like you and I.
Tomorrow, day two, we're gonna
be talking about designing your
membership for retention and renewal.
And then on day three, Thursday, we're
gonna help you finish your roadmap over
the next ninety days for your membership,
regardless of where you're coming from.
My goals for the summit, number
one, I wanna help you decide if
a membership is right for you.
If you answered this and you're like,
uh, "I was an A, and I was considering
whether this makes sense for me," I
hope that by the end of the summit
you feel very clear on whether this
does make sense for you and whether
you want to move forward or not.
And if you do, my second goal is
to provide a scaffolding for you to
work from to make your membership
great, make it very, very successful.
Number three, I wanna provide you
with a literal roadmap to build from.
This is something we're
trying that's very new.
It's extremely, uh,
interactive and high-tech.
I'm excited about it.
We'll introduce that here at the end
of this session, but we wanna give
you a literal roadmap to build from.
And then number four, I
hope we have some fun.
I hope we have a lot of fun here on the
stream, in the chat, uh, in our Q&As.
I'm gonna do some live audits for folks
who want to come on screen on Thursday.
So if that's you, uh,
be prepared for that.
I think it can all be very, very fun.
So today we'll have a full overview
of the summit, which we're,
we're kind of doing right now.
We'll talk about who this is for and not
for, what's happening in education in
twenty twenty six, uh, why I personally
love memberships, the four reasons
most memberships fail, what makes a
great membership, and today at the
end of this session, you'll get a link
to start filling out an interactive
audit for where you are right now.
Tomorrow we'll start with a
little bit of a recap of today.
We'll have a fireside chat
with my friend Chad Carson.
Chad is a member of the lab.
He's been a member of
the lab for three years.
When he came to me three years ago, he
had a course that was doing very well.
He was doing cohorts.
They were doing about $200,000 per
year, but he was doing a lot of
launches, and he was thinking about
shifting to a membership model.
Over the course of really about a
year, that first year, he shifted
to a membership model, and in
2025, last I checked with him, he
had earned more than $900,000 from
that membership, which is crazy.
A huge growth.
And so we're gonna talk with Chad
about the decisions he made, the
changes he made, why that has worked
particularly well from, for him,
and what we can learn from that.
We're also gonna talk about the six
drivers of retention and renewal
tomorrow that make your membership
a little bit more sticky, make
people wanna stick around month
after month or year after year.
Give you a preview of what I'm
launching in July, and tomorrow
you'll get an interactive
diagnostic and pricing worksheet.
Thursday, we'll have a brief recap
of, uh, today, and tomorrow we'll
talk about your year one roadmap.
We'll finish building that
out for you specifically.
We'll do some live problem-solving audits.
I wanna spend a lot of time actually
going live with folks here and walking
through some problems, and then I'll
give you some more information on
what our July initiative looks like
if you wanna keep working together.
For folks who are here and bought
the VIP ticket for the summit, I
wanna let you know that after this
session, uh, our VIP Telegram will
open for two-way communication.
So over the next three days, I'm gonna
be in there paying close attention
and answering real questions from you.
You'll be able to post messages to that
Telegram and ask questions, and I'm going
to respond to them as best as I can.
This is a big experiment.
Both, both Telegram groups
are a big experiment.
We've never done this before.
I was really encouraged to try this
out, um, and I'm having fun with it.
I know Telegram can be
a little, uh, spammy.
So if you join the Telegram and you're
suddenly getting spam messages from
other people on Telegram, I'm sorry.
It is a big bummer.
It's not, uh, something I want to invite
into your life, and I don't like that
Telegram is set up, so you have to
literally subscribe to a paid Telegram
plan to prevent that from happening.
So we'll learn.
We'll see, is this worthwhile?
Is the Telegram, uh, s- uh, session
and Telegram chat really worthwhile?
We will see.
Uh, we'll let you know here
at the end of this program.
Like everything we do here at Creator
Science, I am going to literally,
like, take everything we've learned
about this summit and create content
around it, tell you what we've learned,
help you, help you out with that.
Uh, also for VIPs, we will
have a live Q&A on Friday.
So the summit, for the most part, is
today through Thursday, but then on
Friday at one o'clock, we're gonna
have a live Q&A that'll actually be in
Zoom, so everyone's just on one call.
And, um, I'll stay there and answer
questions for as long as I can.
If you're not in VIP already, and
this sounds like something that's
interesting to you, you can still
join and do that, um, with the QR code
here or at membershipsummit.com/vip.
You can go there and, and join us.
Uh, I'm seeing some stuff in the
chat asking about recordings.
Recordings will be posted
after each session.
Um, for VIPs, you'll have
permanent recordings.
For folks who, uh, did not get VIP,
the recordings will be available for
forty-eight hours after they are posted.
Okay?
I'm gonna leave this on screen for
one more second for anyone else
that wants to join VIP, uh, but
then we're gonna move forward.
Five, four, three, two, one.
Here we go.
All right, let's talk about the
product landscape here in 2026.
And if you notice that subtle
animation and gradient on these
loops, that is my beautiful wife,
Mallory, just making incredible,
exquisite slides here in Canva.
I cannot believe how good these
slides are that Mal has made.
So enjoy that.
I'm gonna go back and I'm gonna
go forward again just so you see
it in case you missed it, okay?
Keep an eye on these loops.
We're going back, and here we go forward.
Ah, so pleasing.
So nice.
So nice
So my belief is that courses are in
trouble, and this can be taken to an
extreme in saying, like, courses are dead.
I'm not here to say that courses are
dead, and if courses are working in your
business still in twenty twenty-six,
ride that wave as long as you can.
I think that courses are in trouble,
um, for information that is less
technical, less difficult to ascertain.
So folks who might still have
good success with courses.
Uh, we have a member in the lab
actually who has, like, very in-depth
knowledge and experience in an
industry that is difficult to get,
and there's a lot of nuance there.
So in situations like that, I think
courses still have some room to go.
Uh, but I do believe that the way that
we have experienced and sold courses as
educational creators for the past several
years, I think we've probably reached
a peak that we will never reach again.
I think that overall, the opportunity with
courses is probably in terminal decline
It's not just that information
is free and abundant, because
that has always been true.
Information has always
been free and abundant.
Information wants to be free.
Derek Sivers, who's had-- who's
been on my podcast, had a great
interaction with him, by the way.
He once said, "If information was
all we needed, we'd all be rich
and have six-pack abs." Information
has always been free and abundant.
It's the way that we access
information that has changed.
The way we access information
has changed quite a bit.
Here's what's changed
here in twenty twenty-six.
It used to be that information
was free but scattered.
Now, information is free and aggregated
because LLMs have taken, like, all of
human knowledge and aggregated it together
so that instead of going to Google and
searching something and then trying to
sift through the results to find the
best single result that we could find,
we now interface with one of these LLMs
who takes this information,
puts it together, and provides
a single response for us.
We don't have to go and
identify the stuff ourself.
It used to be that information
was extrapolated from a source.
We would find a single source, we would
read what they say, and we would try
to extrapolate that information, that
wisdom, to our own personal situation.
But now with LLMs, information
is super personalized to us.
We don't have to extrapolate.
We can ask a question, explain to it our
situation, and have that information given
to us in an extremely personalized way
It used to be that courses
were an efficient-ish solution.
It used to be that we could take, uh,
this course information and work through
a linear journey that was kind of like
a best fit version of the information.
Because as a course creator, what I
basically had to do is say, "Here's
what I know about, um, my audience.
Here's what I know they want to
achieve, and here's where I know they
typically start and where they're
trip- typically trying to end." And
I would create a, a linear journey to
try and get most people from a standard
starting point to the same end point.
But now that everything can be
personalized so much, courses
don't feel very efficient at all.
They feel depersonalized, and they
feel like I'm being kind of shoved
as a round peg through a square hole
As course creators, it also used to be
that you could give information away
for free, but charge for the curation.
So the model for a lot of us was
like, we're creating free content all
the time, and a lot of stuff that we
sell in our courses is stuff that we
have shared for free on our YouTube
channel, in our essays, wherever.
But the curation and ordering and
sequencing of that was valuable
and worth buying a paid course for.
But now, savvy internet users can go
to our entire catalog of free content
and actually create personalized
education with our own free content.
It's just the way things are going.
It's, it's a, it's a genie that I don't
think we can put back in the bottle,
but it's changing what we see value in
You might have seen this essay that
Tim Ferriss wrote, um, two weeks ago.
It certainly made the rounds online and,
uh, got a lot of people's attention.
It was titled, "Has AI Already Killed
How-To Nonfiction?" Talked about his
sales trends, his personal data, and
what it might mean for the future
And this is what he shared.
He shared his year-over-year
book sales information.
So he used twenty
twenty-two as the baseline.
In twenty twenty-three, his c- his
book sales decreased five percent.
In twenty twenty-four, they
decreased thirteen percent.
In twenty twenty-five, they
decreased forty-six percent.
And so far in twenty twenty-six,
he's projecting a fifty-seven percent
decrease over twenty twenty-five.
So he has seen massive drop in book
sales, and he extrapolates from this.
He makes his own predictions and
asks the question: Is prescriptive
nonfiction the canary in the coal mine?
And I'll call your attention to
this, uh, highlighted bit here.
He says, "My position, and I genuinely
love to be wrong, is yes, prescriptive
nonfiction is the canary in the coal
mine, and the coal mine is enormous."
His perspective, his, uh, belief is
that prescriptive nonfiction, including
how-to YouTube videos, prescriptive
podcasts, online courses, newsletters,
advice blogs, he think that-- he thinks
that it's not that it's gonna disappear
completely, but that this is gonna be
source material that we interface with
through LLMs, which, to read another
way, is going to make it inherently more
difficult to charge for this information.
So where does that leave us as
traditionally merchants of prescriptive
non, uh, fiction information?
There are a few, uh, product models
that I'm personally bullish on.
Uh, I shared this at the personal
IPO summit that my friend
Chanel ran earlier this month.
There are some changes that I'm
seeing to how, um, creators like
us, mostly educational creators, are
changing the way that we monetize.
Excuse me.
I think we're gonna see a lot more
people moving from do it yourself
style products to done with you
or done for you style products.
I have spent more time in the last couple
of months tossing around and considering
a world where I have a done for you agency
style offering than I have in years,
because people will never stop paying for
outcomes, and there's no shorter line to
an outcome than hiring somebody to get
you personally, directly to the outcome.
And, uh, there's gonna be a
demand for that continuing.
I think more people are gonna
move towards it because it.
They can feel that demand.
Done with you is kind of
the hybrid in the middle.
It's a little bit like, um, a little
bit like what we're doing here, where
I'm giving you some information.
You're still gonna have to take some
action, but I'm gonna be there to
give you feedback along the way.
More so like a cohort-based course fits
into this done with you sort of model.
I'm bullish on time-bound
experiences, experiences where we
have a, a set start and end time.
An example here, um, you guys might
have seen Jessie Jean on Instagram.
She's doing this Yap challenge right now.
Time-bound challenge is alive and
well because we like things in our
mind that we can put into a clear box.
Not everybody, but a lot of times
people are like, "I want to commit
to something, and I wanna commit to a
certain period of time." I think community
experiences are going to get more and
more important because even if we are
spending more time than ever interfacing
with LLMs, with these chatbots on our
phones, that's not going to eliminate
our desire for socialization and social
experiences, being around other people.
In fact, I think it's
going to heighten it.
Personally, I have spent more time
this year seeking out and building
in-person community here in my,
like, neighborhood with my friends
than I have in a very long time.
Like, I just crave being
connected to more and more people.
I think offline experiences,
as I'm saying, uh, are a
natural extension of that.
Community experiences
happen online and offline.
I think offline experiences, even if
they aren't community experiences,
are really, really important.
We're gonna see more AI-enabled products.
A lot of folks in the lab are
playing around with this right now.
Uh, seeing more and more people say,
"Okay, if AI is changing the way I
deliver information, what if I become
one with or work with AI to make a
superior product delivery mechanism?"
Sponsorships and partnerships.
This has been a long-standing point,
uh, part of, uh, a lot of creators
online, especially, um, social media,
entertainment, YouTube creators.
I don't think that's going anywhere.
In fact, I think this is increasing.
We've seen just a growth in advertising
spend from traditional TV and media
to, uh, social media and content
creators, so this is growing.
This has become a larger part of
our focus here at Creator Science
And affiliates as well.
Uh, affiliates is similar to sponsorship
and partnerships, but there's, um,
less risk on the f- on the front
end for brands, and you get to share
in the success of your campaigns.
Both of these last two, sponsorships and
partnerships and affiliates, they do not,
um, come… Or they, they come with an
element of dependency on a third party,
which I don't love, but they're there.
They are an opportunity
So to kind of round out the Tim
Ferriss story here, he concluded
with some predictions that he
thinks the market for information
is collapsing into the chatbot.
The market for transformation, for sitting
with one mind at length on a subject
that has, it has bled for, might just get
smaller, weirder, and more interesting.
So how do you do that?
He says his, uh,
prediction is three points.
Number one, find your thousand true fans.
If you start off doing this well but
have meandered, it's time to revisit.
Be ve- get very clear on
who those 1,000 people are.
Number two, surprise and delight them.
Over deliver again and again.
And then number three, success.
The team is thinking about this
a lot here at Creator Science
with, uh, our membership, The Lab.
In essence, this is the space where we
serve our thousand true fans, and we will
never run out of appetite and ability
to surprise and delight those people.
Like, if you have customers, it serves
you well to just spend more time
thinking, "How can I over deliver
and better deliver for my customers?"
Versus trying to find new customers
over and over and over again.
All of this, in my opinion, points to
memberships being a big opportunity, a
great product model, and typically or, or,
uh, genuinely what I'm looking at for a
lot of creators here in twenty twenty-six.
Because memberships combine a lot
of these things I was pointing to.
I didn't even highlight in
this the done with you, which
memberships offer done with you
style education in a lot of cases.
You could have AI enable
aspects of your membership.
Uh, you can work with brands and partners
and have them come into and serve your
audience inside a membership as well.
Same with affiliates.
So memberships represent a lot of what
I'm bullish about moving forward, and I
assume that's why you're here as well.
I think you see this opportunity
a little bit intuitively, but this
might have given you a little bit
more, um, rigor and strength behind
why we're thinking about this
So why do I specifically love memberships?
First, let's do the most obvious reason.
If we look at-- this is my
P&L for the business since it
started in twenty seventeen.
Okay?
So we can see pretty clearly here
that we had an inflection point in
twenty twenty-two, which continued
in twenty twenty-three and twenty
twenty-four, followed by a short drop
off last year in twenty twenty-five.
The lab started in twenty twenty-two.
That's the spoiler of this image.
The lab started in twenty twenty-two
and put us on a major new trajectory.
But what happened in twenty twenty-five?
Why did we have a step back last year?
In twenty twenty-five, we saw
a decrease in digital product
revenue by seventy-four percent.
We saw a decrease in sponsorship
revenue at thirty-eight percent.
We saw an increase in affiliate revenue,
a hundred and forty-eight percent.
We saw an increase in membership
revenue by eighteen percent.
So even though twenty twenty-five
was a step back in overall revenue,
our membership revenue continued
to grow in twenty twenty-five.
Our membership revenue
has grown year over year
The Lab, our membership, has been
the stabilizer of the business.
Through having a child and, like,
learning what it's like to run a business
while being a parent, uh, through, uh,
just the chaos that has been twenty
twenty-six, The Lab, our membership, has
been the stabilizer for our business.
I recently attended a author's retreat in
Tennessee with a bunch of fancy people.
I had no business being
in this room, by the way.
I truly do not know why I was invited to
this room, but I was so glad to be there.
You see me in the front here, uh,
also centered in this picture somehow.
But one night over dinner, I was seated
between Nathan Barry from Kit and James
Clear, and they're longtime friends.
I'm friends with both of them.
They've been friends for much longer
than I've known, uh, either of them.
And so I'm sitting there at dinner with
the two of them, and the subject goes
to what is the ultimate business model?
Like, the two of them just were
having fun talking about what is
the ultimate business model to build
the, like, best business possible.
And, uh, ultimately, spoiler,
we, we landed on banks.
None of us are going to build banks,
but the two aspects that they talked
about that make a really strong, really
valuable business: number one, recurring
revenue, revenue that once you earn
it, it's going to repeat over time; and
number two, expansion revenue, meaning
that once you have a customer, there's
a genuine reason or mechanism why their
spend with you would increase over time.
So it's when you, when you have a
customer, number one, they wanna keep
paying you, and number two, they are
willing to pay more over time because
of the value you are providing.
Okay?
So this is something that we
can take and say memberships
provide both of these things.
That's part of the reason why
memberships are so value-valuable.
The recurring revenue part is obvious,
but depending on how you design the
membership itself, you might have multiple
tiers, you might have add-ons, different
experiences that are optional that
represent some expansion revenue as well.
For most businesses, for most
products, you have this pay
once sort of, uh, arrangement.
You know, courses, digital products,
affiliates, one-off services, those
things are pay once and then it's over.
You deliver the outcome,
hopefully both parties are happy,
but that relationship ends.
And then number two, the second
model is a recurring model where the
transaction, the relationship doesn't end.
They pay again.
Memberships, retainers, subscriptions.
When you have this pay again
model, this recurring revenue
model, revenue compounds over time.
It just grows and grows and grows.
And let's, let's put some math
and, and numbers to this to make
this, uh, a lot more obvious
A one-time purchase when it's made
in month one, let's say you have
a $50 digital product or a course.
If that purch- product is
purchased, month one you earn $50.
By month 12, that $50 is still
the same $50, and by month 24,
that $50 is the same $50 because
they made the one-time purchase.
But if somebody purchased a
membership that was $50 a month and
they had a good experience and they
wanted to stick around, by month
12, that's $600 in revenue, and by
month 24, that's $1,200 in revenue.
Like, it's just pretty nutty how different
these scenarios are when you, um, have
recurring versus one-time payments
Memberships provide predictability,
and predictability changes
how you run your business
Let me show you why predictable
income changes the way you run
your business and what you build.
Number one, predictable revenue
gives you permission to hire.
I recently had a conversation
with, uh, Rob Walling, who's
the founder of, uh, MicroConf.
Before that, he actually built Drip,
which is an email marketing platform.
Uh, but now he's doing MicroConf.
He has a, um, investment
tool called TinySeed.
He has a media empire, and
we're talking about hiring.
And he told me he's-- he said that
the great thing about recurring
revenue in software and in
memberships is that this gives you the
confidence to hire and build a team.
Which again, from my own experience,
100% can agree, uh, that now that,
um, I see, okay, I have literal
years' worth of data of how much
revenue the membership generates, I
feel so much more comfortable hiring
Number two, it gives you permission
to build and make longer term bets.
When you aren't so worried about
rev- where revenue is coming from
next month, it allows you to make
decisions that are longer term.
You're not saying, "What do I do this
week to generate re- uh, revenue next
month?" It's, uh, number one, how
do I continue serving my customers
so that they have a good experience
and they wanna keep renewing?
We'll talk a lot about that tomorrow.
And number two, what is the best
long-term decisions we can make
for the business this month?
And number three, and this is one
of my favorites, having predictable
income changes what you can say no to.
You know, it changes your options.
It gives you more options, and there's
nothing more important, I think, than
feeling the freedom to say no to things
that you simply don't want to do.
Because in our businesses as creators,
nothing matters more than the trust we
have with our audience, and if we are
making decisions that are short term and
not in alignment with our audience because
we feel like we have to, we can't say no
to the opportunity, that's a big problem.
Um, I often see partnerships that to
me feel out of alignment, inauthentic,
and I think it's because the revenue
opportunity is there, and people
aren't comfortable saying no.
So having recurring revenue in
your business gives you that
permission, that ability to say no
But this is about more than money.
I wanted to start there because it's
obvious and it's kind of an elephant
in the room and I can show it very
visually like, yes, the membership
that I have has fundamentally changed
my business, has changed my life,
but this is about more than money.
Communities shape who we are.
And I wanna tell you a
little bit of a story.
And here in a minute we're gonna get to
some of the Q&A in the chat, uh, just
to take a little bit of a breather.
But I wanna start with a
little bit of a story here.
When I was in high school, um, we would
every summer get our equipment checked
for, uh, the upcoming football season.
They would measure us for
shoulder pads and, and, uh,
thigh pads, but also helmets.
And every year when I went in to have
my head measured for a helmet, it was
the same guy and he didn't remember
me but I remembered him every year.
Every year he would say, "Hmm,"
and he would measure and remeasure
and he would say, "Okay, you're
too big for a medium I think but
you're also too small for a large."
One year he said, "You're a tweener."
And I just felt like that term so
perfectly described the way that I
have always felt as a person . Meaning
that I have always felt like I'm in
the space between different groups.
Uh, I never felt like I belonged
perfectly to one, uh, one friend
group or one professional group.
I always felt like I could blend
in places but like I never fully
felt like I was in a specific place
So for as long as I can remember,
I have found or built communities.
It started when I was in college.
Um, I found this organization
called the Business Builders Club.
It was the entrepreneurship club at
Ohio State, and it was incredible.
These people were so welcoming, and I just
made that my home for like four years.
So this photo in particular, I was, uh,
in much better shape and kind of ripped.
This is my senior year,
and I was leading the, the
entrepreneurship club at Ohio State.
And between our executive team and the,
the, the club as a whole, this felt like
a place that I could start to belong
And then towards the end of college and
just out of college, I organized a lot of
startup weekend events in Columbus, Ohio.
Um, so I would, I would run these
three-day… I see some patterns here.
This was a three-day, uh, live event, uh,
called Startup Weekend, where we would
help people ideate and start startup
companies, like software companies.
We would have designers,
developers, entrepreneurs.
People would come with ideas, and
over the course of the weekend, it was
Friday evening through Sunday evening,
we would build out a prototype, and
we would talk to customers, and we
would, like, have a competition.
It was awesome.
Um, and so the, the Columbus
startup ecosystem was my community.
And then I started exploring the
online world around 2017, and the
first thing I did after I quit my
tech job to go out on my own was I
joined Seth Godin's Alt MBA program.
And this was, uh, a Zoom call in that Alt
MBA program, early cohort-based course.
We would literally have, like,
six-hour sessions on a Saturday.
It was crazy that we were
spending this much time.
These people were so committed to
it, and these people, like, really
identified with Alt MBA, the program.
Uh, man, I'm seeing some chat,
some chatter in the chat.
People are recognizing
folks from, uh, Columbus.
Love that.
But yeah, this, um, this Alt MBA
program was so eye-opening to me.
I was like, "I can't believe how
much these people, like, love and
identify with this space and this
community." And it's because a lot of
the people in the program, they felt
like tweeners in their work life.
They felt like they were ambitious
and, uh, committed and working
really hard, but they just didn't…
couldn't meet other people like
them in their day-to-day life.
And f- s-suddenly in Alt MBA, these were
people who just felt like their people
On the back of that, I started my first
community called Unreal Collective.
It was a community for
founders and freelancers.
Um, we built this over…
This was essentially, uh,
facilitated mastermind groups.
I would work with groups of five,
and we would have three or four
groups at a time, and I would do
that cycle two or three times a year.
So from 2017 to 20- to 2020, I worked with
about 120 founders and freelancers through
these mastermind programs, and on the back
end of that, we had a Slack community.
Now, this is gonna sound kinda
crazy, but in 2017, I had to teach
people how to download and use Zoom.
Okay?
Like, nobody had used Zoom before in 2017.
When I shifted from Google Hangouts
to Zoom, people were like, "What
is this? How do I do this?" And we
used Zoom for the calls, and we had
a Slack for in-between calls, and
after people had finished the 12-week
program, they stuck around in Slack.
And one of the people that I met
through that experience was Matt
Gartland, who lived in Columbus as well.
He was running a creative agency, and
he had an idea that he was working on.
But he experienced this cohort, he
experienced what I did in Slack,
and shortly after we did that
program together, his agency was
acquired by Smart Passive Income,
and he became the COO, eventually
co-CEO, of Smart Passive Income.
And in 2020, when they were starting
to build SPI Pro, their membership
community, he asked me to come in
and consult and help them build out a
community on this brand-new tool they
had access to in beta called Circle.
I think we were within the first five,
uh, accounts that existed on Circle.
So we did that.
We launched it.
We had great success.
I led the community team for SPI
through 2021, as I shared, and
then in 2022, I went back out on my
own and started building The Lab,
which as I shared, we just had our
in-person event in Boise this month.
It's been life-changing.
Um, so, you know, that's my story
with community, because it's just so
important to me, and this is just,
uh, what our offline experience
looked like last year in Boise.
We had a little video commission.
It's, it's just so powerful.
Like, communities shape the way we, we
think, who we are, what we wanna do.
It's incredible
Communities have changed my life, and I
imagine they've changed yours as well.
So I'd love to hear from you
in the chat what communities
have impacted you, changed your
life, shaped who you are today
I'm gonna look here in the chat and
read some of these out because I'm
always curious to do this, this research
Hey, I see the lab.
Thanks, Kyle.
Running
Esports, Generalist World, Wandering
Aimfully, Toastmasters, Rental
Property Mastery, Future Pro, Ali
Abdaal's live YouTube cohort, SPI
Pro, Nova Scribes, World Domination
Summit, Neurodiversion Summit.
I never got into Chris Guillebeau's stuff.
It was, it was before my time.
Church communities, totally.
Learn dot community, Tom's
community, that's amazing.
Wandering Aimfully, improv, Ship 30
for 30, Self-Care Society, the ADHD
community, local mothers support group,
LinkedIn, Write Grow Sell, Safe Space,
Accountability Success
Circle, All NDA, Vistage.
I'm not sure what NOLS is,
but I'm gonna look it up.
Priya Parker, great book.
Hiking, Wandering Aimfully,
Akimbo, inner development goals.
Okay, this is so fun.
This is so fun.
Look how diverse this is.
Look how wide-ranging this is.
That is the amazing, magical
thing about community
So bottom line, community isn't new.
We've always wanted
belonging and becoming.
But the hard thing about community,
this isn't in my slide deck, the
reason that I stopped doing a lot of
like the local community stuff like
startup weekends, it's a lot of work.
And a lot of times it's thankless
work, and you can get burned
out because you have to be-- you
have to hold space for people.
If you're empathic, it
can take a toll on you.
And if there's not a sustainable
model behind it, people just
get burned out, you know?
And that's why I think memberships
are a great alignment of incentives
between you and your members because
the, the payment required to join
the membership is also what makes
the program inherently sustainable.
And we want a community that is
sustainable, that continues, that
persists, because if we love that
space, we want it to continue to exist.
You can create that transformation for
people, and that's what I wanna help
you do over the next two-plus days
It's something I've been
talking a lot about recently.
I was on Ali Abdaal's podcast
a couple years ago to help
him launch his membership.
Um, and then last year at Craft
and Commerce, I spoke with Nathan
Barry about the future of education,
kind of predicted where things
were going with, with courses.
I think we're still gonna see
some of that play out, but this
is, this is what I'm doing.
This is what I wanna help you with.
Before we talk about parallel
versus shared experiences, I
wanna do a quick time check, okay?
And I'm gonna jump in and look
at some of the questions that
we had in the Q&A real quick
To everyone asking about the
recording, we will send the
recording after the event, okay?
We will have, we will have recordings
Okay, this is an interesting
question from Anthony that I'm
going to, uh, broadcast to the room.
He asked, "Do memberships make
sense for people that want to be a
career coach?" Memberships, as we'll
talk about, are extremely flexible.
I am of the mind that as creative people,
we can create memberships for just about
any, uh, vertical or niche or experience.
I think there can be a membership there.
The question is going to become,
when you think about your own, uh,
needs and desires for how you wanna
interface with the thing, can we find
a shape that makes sense for you?
And it's all a design exercise.
We'll talk more about that here, uh,
later today and tomorrow as well.
Um, ch-ch-ch
We had a question from
Amaris that I'll share here.
"Curious about any thoughts, insights on
memberships for ac- for academies, i.e.,
it includes an ex- an extensive multi-year
curriculum, community space, monthly
calls, et cetera, so a bit of everything.
Because it's unique, and I'm struggling
to nail down pricing and structures."
Yes, I think this is possible, but
the trap that you might fall into
with this line of thinking is you
don't want to make a membership that
just feels like a bunch of stuff.
Like, we need to unite the idea of all
the stuff you get underneath a very
legible promise that you're making, and
we'll talk more about that here shortly.
So I'm just gonna keep
pressing forward here.
Thank you guys for sharing your questions.
We'll have lots of time at the
end to answer more of these.
Okay, let's talk about parallel
versus shared experiences because
this is something that I'm
thinking about a lot these days.
There are two ways to
experience the same thing.
There's parallel experiences, and
there are shared experiences, and
let's, let's think of it this way.
I love the NFL, and I can't wait for
the season to start, and when the season
starts, I'm going to sit down and, uh,
watch Red Zone for possibly seven or eight
hours a day, and I'm gonna love that.
But what I love more than watching
Red Zone on a Sunday is being active
in my fantasy football group chats,
where everyone else is also watching
Red Zone, and we're reacting to the
same things at the same time, and we
have shared stakes because we're in
that fantasy football league together.
So fundamentally, whether I'm watching
that broadcast alone or with other
people, I'm watching the broadcast.
The content is the same.
But the experience is super different
because the experience that I truly love
is less about the content, the thing,
and more about the shared experience
of watching it with other people.
That is the ultimate fun that I have, and
I do it for a lot of things, you know?
When I watch, uh, The Bachelor on a
Monday night with my wife, part of
that is like The Bachelor is a train
wreck, and I see someone in the chat
saying Love Island, same concept.
It's a train wreck, and it's fun to watch.
But I love watching it with my wife.
I love having that shared experience,
and we have friends who watch it
too, and now we're in a group chat
with them, texting them about it
and having that shared experience.
That is the magic of shared experiences.
Whether you're watching a football game
or, uh, listening to a new album that
was dropped or watching a TV series
or eating, you know, having a meal,
reading a book, doing these things
with other people makes for a different
overall experience and outcome and fun.
It's just better Most courses historically
have been parallel experiences.
People who are doing the same thing.
Like you might have dozens or
hundreds of students who are
going through your course, but
they're all doing it in parallel.
You might have hundreds of people
reading your, uh, paid newsletter,
but they're doing it in parallel.
Um, YouTube is kind of an interesting
in-between here where, you know,
people watching your videos, they're
probably having an individual experience
unless they're in the comments.
But if they're in the comments, are
they truly having a conversation
or are they talking at each other?
Like are they coming back?
Are they building relationships?
Most things that creators
produce are parallel experiences.
Uh
And to me, that is suboptimal.
It's, it's just, um, it's not that
it's completely suboptimal, it's that
there's a missed opportunity here.
Memberships with a real community element
are designed to create shared experiences.
They take these parallel things and
basically open up a through line,
um, a conversation between people
that has a shared experience then.
And when you have shared
experiences, they provide things
that parallel experiences can't.
Shared experiences add this
level of accountability that
makes it more likely that people
finish what they've committed to
They add an element of real-time
feedback between other people
who are doing the thing.
If you get stuck, if you have a question,
people can answer that question.
We see this with the difference
between a pre-recorded course and a
cohort-based course, both of these things.
You know, real-time feedback is,
"Hey, I, I'm trying to do this
exercise, but I hit this wall.
I have this question,
I'm having this problem.
Can you help me solve it?" In a
pre-recorded course, you hope that
they leave a comment, and then you can
respond to them and get them help, but
that not only slows down the timeline,
it just doesn't always happen reliably.
Having this real-time feedback
can be really, really helpful.
Number three, and this is a huge one,
when you have shared experiences,
you can build actual friendships.
There can be actual connections
that are made between people that
otherwise just wouldn't happen
If you have this, this experience of
people building real relationships
around the thing that you're doing,
you start to build an actual community.
Inside the lab, we have a whole
host of shared experiences.
This past year we had our first
inaugural fantasy football season.
Uh, congrats Chanelle.
I don't think she's here on the stream
here today, but Chanelle Basilio of Growth
Universe won our fantasy football league.
She beat me in the
championship fair and square.
Congrats to Chanelle.
Thank you to James, who
organized this and made sure
that actually got off the ground.
This was member-led.
This is a member-led initiative, people
saying, "Hey, we're in this community.
I care about football.
If anyone here wants to put a league
together, I'm going to do that." We have a
wellness group that Matt in our community
is running, where he said, "I used to
run this for a company that I worked for.
I wanna help people, uh, improve
their health and wellness.
We are creators, we're stressed,
we have lots on our plate, but
that doesn't mean that we should
give up on our health and wellness.
So I'm gonna run a challenge inside the
community to help people get more steps
or be more mindful." That's fantastic.
Another member-led effort.
We had a fantasy Survivor league for
folks in the community who watch Survivor.
We found a website that does like
fantasy football, except for Survivor
attendance or Survivor, uh, players.
And that was a really fun
thing that just added to my
experience of watching Survivor.
It added to my experience
of being in the lab.
That was awesome.
Stan, congrats on winning, if you're here.
We had a morning wake-up crew.
This was led by a man named Cal.
He noticed that a lot of folks
in the community were talking
about trying to be morning people.
He was ex-military.
He wakes up every day at four thirty.
He said, "I wanna help you guys wake up."
He put together a small group experience
inside the community, and we had a
bunch of people who were waking up
earlier than ever before and getting a
lot of work done and feeling like, "I
have changed, uh, what this is like."
These are shared experiences
inside of our shared experience.
I saw a great question in the chat from
Joy, "How are members who are running
these things getting compensated?"
Uh, it depends on the experience.
For people who are just motivated and
wanna do it and they're like, "Hey, can I
do this?" Yes, you can absolutely do that.
If there are shared experiences
that I want to exist and I'm trying
to find somebody to run it, I will
sometimes offer compensation for that.
Um, that could be in cash, that could
be in exchange for membership dues,
it could be in exchange for a credit
towards next year's membership.
I've seen this done in
lots of different ways.
Uh, it kinda depends on you,
your community, your relationship
to the person, uh, what that
experience is supposed to be like.
I think it's super flexible and
between the two of you to figure out
Not everything, uh, needs to be shared.
Like a reference mandable, uh,
reference manual, that's not really
a shared experience by design.
People just referencing things doesn't
need to be a shared experience.
If you have a membership that is
creating a community experience, but
you wanna put evergreen education
and courses inside of it, great.
Like not everything has to be a
shared experience, but certain things
can be more enjoyable and, um, more
transformational if they're shared
Shared experiences are sticky.
It's one of the reasons that people want
to stick around with your membership
So I, I've said a few different types
of words here, and I wanna get, um, on
the same page in terms of vocabulary.
I'm using the term membership a lot.
This is called a membership summit, and
I'm using that term very specifically.
Okay?
My mom's an English teacher.
My older sister's an English teacher.
I grew up with a, a, a love
of the English language.
So let me, let me talk
about this real quick.
I see memberships as distinct from
communities, courses, and subscriptions.
There are similarities, but I think
the differences are important.
Subscriptions are paid products
or experiences with ongoing
benefits and recurring payments.
The value of a subscription is
generally one-to-one and top-down.
For example, Netflix,
premium podcast feeds.
I do think memberships are technically
a subcategory of subscriptions, and
I'll explain that here in a moment.
Communities are peer-to-peer networks
built around a common interest.
As creators, a lot of what we create,
again, as parallel experiences, are
one-to-one broadcast communications
When we start being a curator around
a certain interest group, we naturally
attract people who care about that thing.
Like, I think as creators, we are
also naturally curators, and curators
are people who say like, "Hey, this
is something I care about, this is
something I have knowledge about, this
is something I'm gonna keep exploring
and studying and sharing about."
And that is what organizes people
around you because they have a
shared interest around that thing.
But it's still one-to-one until you
become a community builder and you
start to connect people to one another.
All of these lines between these circles,
these are bridges and valuable, um,
these, these are valuable interactions
that become possible in a community
space where no longer do we have to go
through you to talk with one another.
This is actually where we
connect with one another
Peer-to-peer networks are
not a broadcast channel.
Peer-to-peer networks generate
value from the other members, and
peer-to-peer networks are in service
to the nodes of that network.
They exist to serve all of the
different nodes in that network.
So a community is a place where people
can connect and learn from one another.
It can be free, it can be paid, it
can be a part of another product,
like a course or a membership.
Um, an example here might be a
listener community for your podcast.
Community just means a group of people who
are connecting around a common interest
A course is a paid product or experience
with one specific desired outcome.
It's typically a linear journey, a
prescriptive linear journey that is
a singular individual experience.
Courses can be re- prerecorded
and self-paced, or they can be
live, like a cohort-based course,
which is kind of a hybrid.
And then memberships, as I was
saying, I would actually place this,
um, as a subcategory of subscription
because it's a subscription product.
It's a recurring transaction
that provides access to typically
community and other kinds of courses.
So like you'll sometimes hear
things called a membership that
I would just call a subscription.
Like to me, a membership means
there is a community experience.
Is, um, having a AAA
membership a membership?
In my mind, it's more of a subscription.
You know, it's more of a
content and perks subscription.
If I am not connecting with
other people, to me, that's not a
membership, it's simply a subscription.
A purely content-based membership
where there's not communication,
to me, again, feels like a content
subscription more than a membership.
So to me, the value of a membership
includes a peer-to-peer aspect, which
means that the value of a membership
is a little bit out of your hands.
It changes all the time.
Um, a community is typically a
major part of a membership, but
it doesn't have to be all of it.
But to me, a membership needs to
have a community aspect to truly be a
membership and not just a subscription.
A little bit of this is semantics, but
this is how I'm using my vocabulary in
this presentation over the next few days.
So communities versus memberships,
'cause I'm seeing some questions.
Is a paid membership community different
from a membership and a community?
To me, communities promise connection
and the value is from the members.
Memberships promise value.
Value can and probably does come from
members, but it might also include access
to the creator, uh, workshops, course
discounts, software discounts, additional
free content, affiliate opportunities.
Like to me, memberships can have a
lot of aspects of value within them
outside of the community, or it
could just be the community itself
Memberships as a form factor
have a lot of variability then.
A lot of the questions I had leading up to
this summit, and even in the chat here so
far today, are around this idea of like,
will memberships work for my situation?
I don't want it to eat up all of my time.
I get it.
I hear all of that.
These are super valid concerns, but
I think they're all solvable concerns
through the way you design the experience
So before we talk about, uh, how
to design the experience and how
to make a great membership, I wanna
talk about why most memberships fail
There are four reasons why most
memberships fail number one
is lacking a clear promise.
We're gonna talk about all
four of these number two is
lacking care from the creator
Number three is lack of direction
and number four is lack of villagers.
We're gonna dive into all of those
Uh, I see a question in
the chat from Deborah.
Could Jay give an example of what circle
community is not a membership community?
Again, part of this is,
is a little bit semantics.
Um, if you have a circle community
that is completely free, to
me that is just a community.
I don't see that as a membership
because it's not a paid, uh, product.
It's not a paid subscription
Okay, let's keep moving forward on these
So what does it mean to have
lack of a clear promise?
This means if people don't know what your
membership does for them, they won't buy.
If it's not clear what you're
doing for me, I'm not gonna buy it.
I'm not gonna be interested
Potential customers aren't going
to work that hard to try and
understand the thing that you sell.
Like, we're, we're simply not walking
around saying like, "Gosh, I just wanna
spend money on something. Somebody
give me something to spend money
on." We're inundated with options
for spending money, so our default is
trying to, um, uh, disqualify things.
Like, I want to very quickly
feel like this is not for me,
so I can not think about do I
wanna spend money on that thing?
So your community, your membership
needs to be so clear in what it
offers to people that they can't
disqualify it because it's clearly
something they value and they want.
At least some people, okay?
If you're not clear very quickly,
people just won't purchase because
they don't care enough to do the work
to understand why they should care.
They're trying to answer the
question why should I care?
When you are marketing your thing,
when you're making your thing, when
you're designing your membership,
people need to know why should I care?
Because if they don't know why they
should care, they're not going to care
Problem number two, lack
of care from the creator.
Sales and content, I would say, is a
transfer of emotion and enthusiasm.
Our audiences naturally care about
the things that we obviously care
about because our enthusiasm, our
emotion transfers to those people.
And this is true after the sale
as much as it is before the sale.
If we can tell that you or your team
aren't excited about the thing that
you've made, i.e. your membership, we're
not gonna be excited about it either.
Why should we care about something
that clearly you don't care about or
don't wanna spend a lot of time within?
It doesn't mean that you always
have to be available, by the way.
If you have a design constraint
that you don't wanna spend every day
in the community or all day in the
community, we can solve for that.
But your level of care should
shine through in the way the
design of the experience is made.
Even if you're not always available,
when you are available, the way that
you've created the space, the way it
provides value to your members, it
should be clear that there was care
put into the design of that experience
and what people are doing there.
Otherwise, the experience that pe-
a lot of people have in that space
is like, "Is anybody in charge here?
What's going on?
Why is it, why does it feel
like this is, uh, directionless,
aimless, uh, kind of a free-for-all?
What's going on here?" Speaking
of directionless, this is one
of our other points of failure,
having a lack of direction.
A lot of memberships feel like a sandbox,
and some memberships feel more like a map.
Sandboxes aren't necessarily bad.
They give you, like, the space
to explore and try things out.
But to get value out of a
sandbox, you need to have, like,
natural time and curiosity.
You have to want to explore and
spend time indulging your curiosity
But in a lot of spaces, people
like to be told what to do.
It just feels easier.
They want to be given the
direction for where they should
go, what they should do next.
The more direction you give people, the
more likely they are to be successful.
Without any direction, you're probably
gonna deal with confusion, which
leads to inaction, which leads to
inactivity, which leads to churn.
So more direction is usually good.
It doesn't mean it has to be totally
prescriptive, because there are
people who will naturally want to
spend more time exploring their
curiosity, trying things out.
But if you have a pure sandbox
without direction, without a map,
this will lead to a lot of problems.
It's kind of like saying like, "Okay,
here is, uh, the key to our gym.
It's open 24 hours.
Good luck." Like, "Here's your key.
Go in and explore." People can do that.
Like, they can take the key and
they can learn things on their own.
But, um, they might be a little
bit uncomfortable the first time
they're encountering different
things within that space.
They might even, might not even be aware
of everything that's available to them.
There might be doors and machines and,
and elements of the experience that
they don't even know they have access to
Number four, the issue of
having a lack of villagers.
I think about this a lot with memberships
and communities broadly right now.
We hear this phrase, everyone wants
a village, but no one wants to
be a villager, and it's so true.
And one of the things that I-- uh,
one of the mantras that I've been
holding for myself this year is be more
of a villager in the spaces, in the
communities that I inhabit and I value
and I want to be strong and sustaining.
How do I do more of my part?
I certainly feel this as a parent.
I read some statistic that, um, it
was like early, uh, early humans
who lived in tribes would average,
like I said, like twelve or fifteen
different people spending time
with a baby, an infant per day.
And here we are, like, living
in a suburb and like most days
we have a part-time nanny here.
So our daughter is seeing my
wife, me, and a part-time nanny.
But a lot of times it's just me and my
wife, and that's why parenting feels hard.
The, the, the idea with parenting
has always been it takes a village.
But if you don't have a village
because nobody wants to be a villager,
then you don't have community.
So in an online space, this looks
like you have a lot of posts with
zero replies or slow responses.
This often happens if you set
an expectation that the value
of this membership is based
on content and consumption.
If I come in expecting that the way I
extract value from the space is consuming
what is posted here, I'm gonna come in
as a consumer and not as a villager.
I'm gonna come in as a
taker and not as a giver.
These spaces have no reciprocation.
They feel like, well, you don't care
about me, so I don't care about you.
It's a lot of two-dimensional names
and faces, a lot of talking at one
another rather than talking to one
another I had one, uh, email leading
up to this where a reader named
Andrea said, "I haven't succeeded
in making the community feel alive.
It's not the go-to place for parents'
questions, even though they love our live
classes, emails, and social content." My
gut, and it would take more exploration
here, but my gut is these people came in
with an expectation that the value of this
membership is in consuming this content.
They didn't come in expecting to be a
villager, and so turning that expectation
around is gonna take a little bit of work.
It actually happens before the sale.
You need people coming in expecting that
this is a community where we are giving,
we're helping, we are as much villagers
as we are, uh, villager, I guess.
We're, we're helping as much as
we are, are, uh, taking away.
So if these are the things
that make memberships fail,
what makes a great membership?
All we have to do is invert these failures
to see what a great membership looks like.
So if failing memberships lack
a clear promise, a successful
membership has a clear promise.
If a failing membership lacks care
from the creator, a successful
membership shows care from the creator.
If a failing membership
lacks direction, a successful
membership has a clear direction.
And if a failing membership
lacks villagers, a successful
membership is full of villagers
So I'm gonna touch on each of these.
I'm keeping an eye on the clock.
I do wanna leave some time for Q&A,
but we're getting, uh, a little
close on time, and I recognize that.
Thanks for hanging with me.
So number one, designing a clear promise.
Your promise needs to be
the intersection of legible,
meaning it's easy to understand.
Something legible is I
hear it and I get it.
An example is, "I help people
lose weight." Okay, I get it.
Compelling, something your
target audience truly cares about
An example might be I help
people lose ten percent of their
body weight in thirty days.
That feels pretty compelling.
Maybe I wanna lose ten
percent of my body weight.
That's actually pretty big.
I probably wanna lose a
little less than ten percent.
Differentiated, how you're
different or better.
Example here would be, I help
people lose ten percent of their
body weight in thirty days without
giving up their favorite snacks.
So you can see how these things
start to stack on each other, and
by the time we get to the end here,
it's just a lot more clear and a
lot more, uh, compelling, you know?
So this can actually be used as a
really helpful diagnostic if we think
about, um, this- these three aspects.
So let me pull up my, my pointer here.
When you are legible, differentiated,
and compelling, that puts you in a
place where it's like, okay, I'm in a
good spot, and I'm poised for growth.
But if you're missing one of these
three, then this is a big problem.
Um, and you can use this as a diagnostic.
So if you're legible and compelling
but not differentiated, you have
entered a competitive hellscape.
People get what you do, and they
want what you do, but they don't
know how you're different, so you
have to out-compete other people.
If you're legible and differentiated
but not compelling, nobody cares.
Like, I get it, and I see how you're
different, but it's not compelling
to me, so I just don't care.
And if you're differentiated
and compelling but not
legible, nobody gets it.
It's like, okay, that sounds
different and maybe kind of
interesting, but, uh, I… What?
What do you do?
So depending on where you feel like
you are getting negative feedback
from the market, do you feel
like you're dying of competition?
Do you feel like nobody cares
when you talk about what you do?
Do you feel like nobody gets what
you're saying your membership does?
These things point to one of
these three aspects failing.
So in the chat, we can try this out.
I would love to hear from you.
Who do you help?
The second question will be, how
do you make their lives better?
And the third question will
be, how are you different?
So I'm gonna pause here
and read some of this.
Julissa helps creative women.
Catherine helps creatives who
are using their art in all
its forms to change the world.
Jen helps older populations.
Marina helps homeschooling
moms of middle schoolers.
I see expecting parents, millennial women
navigating the challenges of dating.
Ah, Amy, I thought that might be you.
Good to see you here, Amy
Post-menopausal women, burnout
attorneys, artists and creatives,
educat- educators and students
professionals in mindfulness
Teachers, ICU nurses
Great
This is the type of thing that
I would keep just working on and
workshopping, trying to get as legible,
compelling, and differentiated as
you can while also being short.
That's a challenge.
Can I say these things
quickly in a short burst?
The old elevator test
I have some examples here.
These aren't gonna be all perfect,
but they're examples that I like,
that I think are diverse, that, um,
might give you some direction here.
I think Dr. Becky is doing a really
good job, and it's really impressive.
The scale of her
community is pretty crazy.
There are more than 100,000
people in her, uh, membership
And her promise is, "Parenting is
hard. Our app makes it easier." So
she helps parents, very legible.
Um, our app makes it easier.
Our app makes parenting easier.
It's not differentiated.
I would say this isn't clearly
differentiated, but if we get down
a little bit more, "This helps you
handle the hardest parenting moments
built by clinical psychologist Dr.
Becky." Of course, she has a little
bit of a benefit of being Dr. Becky.
Like, she's kind of broken through.
So being built by Dr. Becky and
her, um, uh, IP is differentiated.
We don't all have that benefit
of being a known person, but I
like this, I like this example.
Uh, example number two
from Tamara Grzyminski, Lab
member, awesome human being.
Her business or her
membership's called PMM Camp.
PMM Camp is where product marketing,
product marketers build leadership
range so they can move beyond
execution to influence decisions, shape
strategy, and build a trusted team.
But if you go up a level higher, become
an indispensable product marketing leader.
I think that is legible, compelling.
Uh, differentiation is always hard to nail
in the language, but she's in a space that
isn't super competitive, so she gets to
be differentiated again by being her, by
having, like, an obviously clear brand,
by working with some known quantities
We have, uh, Vojta.
He is one of the leading experts
on the circular economy, I think
the biggest LinkedIn, uh, creator
around the circular economy.
His membership helps you plan,
build, and grow a profitable
career in the circular economy
I found this one on the Circle
Discover Mar- Marketplace.
This is new to me, but I liked it.
Uh, Modern Makers where sewists
find their people, build skills,
and sew with joy together
And last, I think Deborah's actually here
hanging out, um, if I'm guessing the right
Deborah from the first, first name here.
Goats 365: Raising Goats
Without Losing Your Mind.
I love that.
Living with, learning about, and
loving goats 365 days a year.
Deborah's got a fascinating business,
but this is, like, just another great
example of how creators are everywhere.
We can do anything, and any
one of us has opportunity.
Like, yeah, if I'm having the experience
of raising goats and I'm losing my
mind and I don't know what I'm doing
because I got so… Oh, wrong Deborah.
Okay.
Sorry, Deborah, I thought it might be you.
Um, if, if I'm having experience with a
goat because someone on TikTok convinced
me that I could have a goat as a pet, um,
maybe I need to learn how to raise goats
All right.
Lastly, showing that you care
This requires you to, uh, have
a lot of intellectual honesty.
And what I'm gonna ask you to do
is look at every aspect of your
membership through your members' eyes.
Your sales language, how you check
in with them, how you onboard them,
the introductions that they make
and how you respond to them, or the
introductions you make for them, the
welcome messages that you send to them.
Do these things show that you care?
Do you clearly show th- through this
experience that you have put thought and
intention and care into this experience?
Another thing I think a lot
about is time to first win, TTFW.
When somebody joins your membership,
they have taken all of the risk because
at that moment they have paid and they
have not extracted any of the value yet.
So when somebody joins, they're
fundamentally shouldering all
the risk of that transaction.
And so it should be your biggest priority
to help them achieve their first win as
quickly as possible to start to shift
or eliminate some of that risk and get
them excited about whatever effort is
required for them to extract the value
you've promised from that membership.
I think about surprise and delight a lot.
There's no way to surprise and delight
without pretty clearly caring about
your people and about the experience.
The way you show up personally, again,
doesn't mean that you're available
all the time, but the way you show
up when you do show up matters a lot.
Ultimately, keeping your
promise matters a lot.
Whatever you're promising
to do with your membership,
keeping it shows that you care.
Creating clear direction At every
turn, when somebody joins your
membership, they're asking themselves,
and you indirectly, "Now what?
Now what do I do?
I just paid for this thing.
Now what do I do?" The longer you
can string together answers to
the now what question, the better.
So here's an example.
This is what we do in the lab.
You make your purchase, the first thing
I ask you to do, complete your profile.
After that, finish your onboarding.
After that, welcome a new member.
This is how I'm trying to plug in the
be a villager, uh, aspect early on.
It used to be it would say, "Okay, you
just completed your profile, uh, introduce
yourself." But actually, what we found
through analyzing the behavior of our
members, members who comment-- uh, or I
should say, our most successful members,
the ones that are happiest, that have
stuck with us the longest, they have
like a five to one comment to post ratio.
And so I thought, okay, what if I could
build this into onboarding, that before
you introduce yourself, what we actually
want you to do is welcome someone else
who has recently introduced themselves.
Then introduce yourself, then schedule
a one-on-one welcome call with
me, then subscribe to the private
podcast, then create your plan,
then attend our next live session.
You know, you can push this
as far as you can push this.
It's a good exercise to see where is
the upper limit on how many times can
I answer the now what question to get
people to their first win, to feel
like they have de-risked their purchase
and like they are on their way to
getting the thing that you promised.
Most memberships are great for the
first few days or weeks and then fizzle
out, and that is what we want to avoid.
We want to not fizzle for as long
as possible, and the more you
can answer this question and give
people a string of wins, the better
And then lastly, cultivating a village.
How do we do this?
How do we get people to
want to be villagers?
Memberships are like gardens.
You can't really make them grow, but
you can create the right conditions
We care for people we feel like we know.
So the biggest reason that people, um,
feel disconnected from a space is that
they never feel like they've connected
a real human being to the other side
of a two-dimensional name and photo.
We care for the people
that we feel like we know.
So you need to get beyond names and
photos using things like live calls,
small group experiences, one-to-one
introductions, offline experiences.
In the beginning, that means that you need
to model what it means to be a villager.
So let me go back one point real quick.
I really cannot recommend enough
finding ways to connect people
one-to-one quickly after they join.
This is another thing we're working on
in the lab right now as part of our,
like, revamped onboarding experience,
is I send one automated email…
Sorry, one automated direct message when
folks join the lab, and what I'm trying
to do is identify who is the best person I
can connect them to as quickly as possible
that's going to help them, um, get through
their next challenge and feel like they
have a friend here in the community
That's what I'm trying to do.
So when you can get people to see names
and faces in a forum as a real person
that they care about and they want to see
succeed, like there's no way around it,
being active in a forum means that there's
some effort that you're putting in.
Why would we do that?
We do it because we
care about those people.
But if we don't care about those
people, I'm not gonna do that.
So we have to create actual exchanges
between people to build that care.
And in the beginning, it's on
you to show what that looks like
So I'm gonna share next steps
for us here in a moment.
Um, but I wanna hear in the chat, after
all we've shared today so far, do you
feel like you're up to the challenge?
We're gonna wrap up here in a couple
minutes, and I'll share what happens next.
But do you feel like you are up
to the challenge that is building,
cultivating, growing a membership?
Are you more interested in building a
membership than you were when you joined?
Let me know
And while you do that, I'm gonna
tell you a little bit about tomorrow
Tomorrow we're going to talk about what
separates memberships people stay in
from memberships they drift away from
We'll have a brief recap of today,
a very brief recap of today.
Again, we'll talk with Chad
Carson, talk about how his business
went from courses to a thriving,
thriving, thriving membership
We're gonna cover the six
drivers of retention and renewal.
I'm gonna give you a preview
of what I'm launching in July
And you're gonna have an interactive
diagnostic and pricing worksheet.
So save the time and place.
We'll start again
tomorrow at the same time.
Same link will work for you.
I hope you save it.
Chad is genuinely awesome.
He's gonna kick things off for us.
He is the man, and I think you're
gonna love learning from him.
So definitely come in early
to meet and hear from Chad.
Immediately following this broadcast,
I'm going to be sharing an interactive
worksheet with you in Telegram, and
then a little bit later in email.
We have an email going out
later with the recording.
But immediately after this
ends, I'll share it in Telegram.
I'm about to show you
what that looks like.
Uh, I'm gonna open up the two-way
communication in our VIP Telegram so that
you can, uh, chat with me throughout.
And if you did still wanna join VIP,
here is the link again to do that.
It's membershipsummit.com/vip.
I think I can even put that on
To the pa… I know I don't,
I don't have that loaded up.
Um, yeah, so th- these are our next steps.
This interactive worksheet
is very, very cool.
This is what's gonna come in Telegram.
So we have a backend toolkit built
into the membership, Membership Summit
website, where we're gonna ask you to
fill in some questions, answer some
questions, and over the course of the
next two days, this is literally going
to start building out your plan for you
The worksheet is not only for VIPs.
No.
Worksheet is for everybody.
That'll come, but if you're not in the
Telegram group, you'll have to wait
for my email later to get it, which is
gonna be after the replay is processed.
So it's gonna take a minute.
Um, worksheet's gonna go to everybody,
and this is gonna start building out
your roadmap over the next three days.
Oh, yes.
See?
There's Ana in the chat
Here is our Telegram for
everybody where this link will go
Okay.
Um, that's what's coming next.
Here's that link again.
I know we are at time, so feel
free to jump if you need to.
I'm gonna stick through, and I'm gonna
answer questions that were in the
Q&A here for the next few minutes.
Um, again, this is the
Telegram link for everybody.
Anybody has access to this Telegram,
and that's where we're gonna drop the
interactive worksheet here shortly.
Um-
And I'm gonna go to Q&A
All right
Here we go.
Question from Chelsea.
Mostly for tomorrow, but thinking
about how to retain people if your
offer is life stage based, i.e.,
I focus on expecting couples.
Obviously, they end up having the baby.
I'm considering just two communities,
and they can move to the current
parent one, but not sure if
that's too confusing too much.
This is difficult from a sales
perspective, um, because obviously people
who are expecting are in like a nine-month
window you gotta capture them in
I think there are multiple ways to
design this, and it's worth designing
different avenues and playing with it.
Like, you could have two
communities, but when you have two
communities, there is certainly a
degree of doubling of the effort.
Like, there's just twice
as much stuff to maintain.
If there are assets that you want to
make available to both communities,
now you're uploading it twice.
So when possible, I try to design for
one community space, one membership,
because also when you have two things,
you now have to market two things.
So any piece of content you create
could be geared towards one or the
other, but not effectively both.
Whereas if you have one membership with
one community, that is just one thing
that you can benefit from repetition to
talk about over and over and over again.
So I would think what is true about
both of these two life stages that I can
tie together in one membership offering
and just sell the one thing, and maybe
there are different spaces within it.
I gave the example of Dr. Becky's
Good Inside app a little bit ago for
parents, and they have, um, you know,
parenting is kind of like the overarching
thing, which in your case, parenting
could also be an overarching thing.
And for them, they have like, okay, there
are, there are identity groups within
it, like I'm a dad versus I'm a mom, or
I'm African American, or I'm Caucasian.
Like, they have all these different
groups within it where they say,
okay, parents is a big umbrella.
What is true for multiple groups
within it that we can give them their
own small space to benefit from?
And I think in your case, Chelsea,
there's probably a version of that as well
Okay, question from Jeanette.
Let me put this up
I love the idea of people
welcoming another member.
I don't have a lot of members coming in.
Would this work the same way if I ask
them to con- to comment on someone's post?
Totally.
Yeah, totally.
I think, um, number one, when new
people are coming into your membership
and introducing themselves, I think
it's incumbent on you as the creator
of the space to have somebody
on your team welcoming everyone.
Um, I think a core differentiator for
the lab, this has been historically true,
I think it's been more true at times in
the past than it has been in the very
recent past, but I really-- I view speed
of response as a competitive advantage.
Because if somebody posts in your space,
especially an introduction post, they
are taking time, they are making effort,
they are being vulnerable, and once
they do that, they have, like, kind of
an uncomfortable feeling of uncertainty
of, "How am I going to be received?
Am I gonna feel welcomed?
Am I gonna feel like people care
about me?" And the longer they wait
before getting any response or,
like, a truly welcoming response,
the harder that feels, and it makes
them less likely to post again.
So I see this as a point of failure for
a lot of memberships, is they do a really
good job of getting people to introduce
themselves, but then the experience
after introducing myself is so bad that
now I no longer wanna use the space
'cause I don't feel welcome, and I feel
like posting here is not productive.
So, uh, any way that you can model
the behavior of welcoming other
people, and then even thanking
people who are being villagers.
This is also important.
This is something I, I should call out.
If you see people in your community
who are being kind to one another
and exhibiting the behavior you
wish more people exhibited, thank
them privately, maybe even thank
them publicly to show, like, this
is allowed and appreciated behavior
Paula asked, uh, let me broadcast this
Do you give them the whole onboarding
journey upfront or drip it over time?
Um, kind of both.
So we have a, a brief, uh, like
orientation course when people come
in, and so the onboarding that I send
them when they come in, they start
getting a drip, uh, direct message,
uh, series, which is I think now
narrowed down to two messages, but
they also get a drip email series.
And when they come in, both the first
direct message, both the, both the first
direct message and the first email is
saying, "Go complete this orientation
course," basically, and it should
take them no more than 15 minutes.
So if they do that, they're
effectively onboarded.
But the email drip kind of assumes
that, like, they may not get all the
way through it, and we wanna reinforce
some of the most important aspects
of it, which for us is subscribing
to the private podcast feed, um,
and scheduling your one-on-one call.
'Cause I know if you do those two
things, uh, you're gonna stay more
connected to the space, and I'm gonna
have the opportunity to, um, triage
any issues that you're having and
get to know a little bit more ab-
a lot- a little bit more about you
Uh, John asks, "It looks like a
lot of this is entrepreneurs and
self-help creators. Will this course
be valuable for purely entertainers?"
John, my bias is towards the
education and transformation side.
I think there's certainly, um, benefit
over the next two days for someone in
your position, uh, more entertainment.
But a lot of the examples and the
way I think about this is on a more
educational and transformational side.
It just is.
It's, it's my experience.
Uh, I think it is harder
to do memberships, uh,
from an entertainment lens.
It tends to look a lot more like a,
uh, content subscription, but I also
think there's opportunity to, uh,
extrapolate what we're sharing in
education to an entertainment setting to
stand out and be a little bit different
Marina asks… I love that you
guys are continuing to stick
around and ask questions.
We have a good group still sticking
around, so I'm gonna keep hanging out
and answering more of these questions.
Marina asks, "Can you talk more
about how you use a private podcast
to engage your members?" We, through
the natural, um, course of doing, uh,
the membership, we end up creating
a lot of assets, a lot of videos.
Like we have live sessions
where I'm teaching.
We have live sessions
that are social sessions.
We have workshops from external guests.
We have like sprints that we do.
So we end up having a
lot of net new assets.
But computer time is limited
for everybody, you know?
And I, I shouldn't need to sit down
at my computer to watch a recording
if I could listen to it and get
90-plus percent of the value.
So the private podcast is a way for me to
say, "Hey, we're all busy." Like everyone
in the Lab, we are professional, mostly
full-time creators, and I recognize
that when you're at the computer, you're
probably working on your business,
and being in the forum every single
day may not be your highest priority.
But if you saw something on the calendar
that you wished you had attended but
couldn't make work, or if you just wanna
like get in and get more of what was
shared there, the private podcast is a
way to do that on the go, in the car, on
a walk, on a run, whatever you wanna do.
Um, so I know that the private
podcast makes members happier and
more connected to the space because
it allows them to connect to the space
without being in the literal forum
Catherine asks, "How long is that
one-on-one call, the onboarding call?" So
at this point it's 20 minutes, Catherine.
It used to be 30 minutes, but I
found that when I shrank it down
to 20 minutes, we still got like
almost all of the same value.
We just got into things a
little bit more quickly.
And a little secret is that I still block
off the last 10 minutes most of the time.
So if we go over the 20
minutes, I'm happy to go over.
But what I didn't like was having an
onboarding call where we got to like the
20 minute mark and it kind of felt like we
were dragging things out to the 30 minute.
So right now, those are 20 minutes
This is a fun question.
This is from Daniella.
If you have learning content,
how do you position that so
that it's a shared experience?
Is it as simple as instructing them to
have watch parties or do we create that?
So I think there are multiple ways
to do this, and I'm going to try to
not to limit your thinking, because
I think this question will allow you
to come up with creative solutions.
But when I was at SPI, we did, uh,
boot camps, live cohorts around Pat's
preexisting courses, and we did a
flipped classroom model most of the
time, where instead of having Pat reteach
something that was already in course
format that you could pause, uh, watch
at one and a half speed, bounce around
in, we did it reversed, uh, flipped
classroom format, where we paced out
the material over a period of time.
So we said, "Okay, we're gonna do a
power-up podcasting boot camp, and it's
six weeks long, and in week one, we want
you to watch these five videos and be
done with them by Monday. Come in Monday,
we're gonna answer your questions about
them. And then Thursday, we're gonna,
um, answer more…" I forget exactly how
we did that between Monday and Thursday.
I'm pretty sure, I'm pretty
sure… Oh, here's what I remember.
Okay.
So it was watch the videos.
Monday was instructor Q&A, and
the Thursday was small groups.
So we, we had them watch the videos.
We did Q&A on Mondays.
On Thursdays, we had a small group
that they were placed in that was
their small group for the whole
cohort, and they would work on
their homework together on Thursday.
So that was one way to turn preexisting
content into a shared experience was,
yes, we made it a time-bound experience.
It's like we're all gonna focus
on doing this course together
over the next two weeks.
We're gonna start here, and we're gonna
pace it out for you, and if you stick
up with it, we're gonna be at this
endpoint together by the end of it
Let's see here
Okay, this is great.
Is there a rule of thumb you use in
allowing members to post in a specific
space instead of limit to admins?
I'm worrying about members posting
something that is not really of value to
others, which then causes other members to
turn off notifications for future posts.
Depending on the tool you use, and
personally I'm a huge advocate for Circle,
you can control default notifications.
So for example, when I run, uh,
cohort-based courses, I will
design them so that there is
homework that you complete before
our next call it lecture, okay?
And that goes into a homework space, and
I set that homework space to not have
notifications, because somebody posting
their homework probably doesn't add a ton
of value to somebody else in the program.
So to me, it's, it's not totally
about… I mean, there are, there
are questions to be asked, like in
announcement spaces in the lab or in
a cohort, members can't post there.
It's admin only, and so I set
the notifications on by default.
Um, some spaces though I want
to be community communication
spaces, and I want people to post.
If you find that people are posting things
that are low value or detracting from the
community, what you wanna do is try to
identify why is this a net negative to the
community experience, and can I create a
policy around that for our guidelines and,
like, um, terms of use so that if that
behavior persists, I can then point to it
and say, "You're breaking our guidelines,
and I'm gonna give you one more chance,
uh, but you can't do this thing anymore."
Mia asks… I'm gonna answer two more
of these questions, and then we're
gonna take a break for tomorrow.
But Mia asks, "Will you talk about
membership pricing at some point?
I love the idea of a welcome call,
but my price is too low to manage
that." Yeah, great question.
Uh, we will talk about
pricing specifically tomorrow.
Talk about pricing tomorrow.
Um, yeah, tomorrow's our,
our big day on pricing
Okay, here's a great question from Elaine,
and then I'm gonna call it for the day.
Elaine asks, "How to
reengage the community?
I have about 200 members, would love
to get people engaging and sharing.
How to start that up?
Me as an admin, I post questions
weekly, and if nobody answers
them…" Dot, dot, dot.
So my big thing for a space that
is disengaged is you need to
point to the elephant in the room.
You need to own it.
You need to name it, because these
people came into the space and they
were hopeful that this would work and
that they would get a lot out of it.
They wanted this to be good, okay?
They wanted this to be good,
but their experience has shown
them that this is not good.
They are let down by this experience
Chances are they still want us to be good,
but they need to see some evidence or some
reason to believe that things will change.
And so I think it's incumbent on you
to step forward and be like, "Hey,
I just want to step forward and own
what I think a lot of us are seeing.
Things have not been very active.
Things have been pretty quiet.
This has not been the experience
any of us truly wanted, so I
am creating a moment to reset.
Here is my plan moving
forward for this community.
Here is my hope for what we do together.
Here is how I, as the creator, uh,
and curator of this space, am going to
act differently, and what I'm asking
for you or of you is this." This
gives people a reason to believe that
things will change if they try again.
Because ultimately, that's
what you're asking them to do.
You're saying like, "Hey, I know that
your experience hasn't been what you
wanted, and so you've kind of written
this off, but I wanna get this going.
I wanna try again." So do that moment
of reset, and my, my favorite way
of doing this is to say like, "We
are going to have a town hall."
I do this once a year in the lab.
We do it every either late January
or early February, where it's the
most important live session we do
every year, and I try to get as
many members as possible to attend
that live session because in that
session, I basically say, "Okay.
Whether you've been really active
lately or not, here's what's
changed over the last year.
Here are some wins that I wanna point out.
I wanna pour love on folks that are,
like, being villagers in the community.
Um, and I also wanna point to
things we are definitely going to
be doing moving forward and create
a discussion for things that you
suggest and would like to see moving
forward." It's, it's a conversation.
Like, some things you'll, you'll already
be saying like, "We're definitely gonna
change this and do this because I've heard
this feedback," but then you wanna open
up space to say, "What ideas do you have?
What thoughts, questions, concerns
do you have?" After that town hall, I
send a member feedback survey that is
completely anonymous, and I have people
rate the different, like, projects and
initiatives that we're talking about
doing, and then we use that as our guide
for making changes throughout the year.
So it starts with, uh, it starts with
stepping forward and saying like,
"Hey, I know this hasn't been what you
wanted, but we're changing it," and
then actually following through on that.
You probably don't get a ton of chances to
do this, like, reset sort of thing, so you
really wanna do it well the first time.
So think about it, make the post,
follow through on it, have that
experience, and you should be good to go.
Um, okay.
I'm gonna call it for today.
I need to take, uh, a drink of water.
I need to take a breath.
I need to take a little bit of a break.
I hope that this has been
super, super, uh, beneficial
and worth your time here today.
Tomorrow, more of the same.
More teaching, except tomorrow we're
talking about retention specifically.
We will talk about pricing a lot tomorrow,
and tomorrow I'm gonna reveal some of
the things that we're working on that if
you wanna work with us further to build
out your membership, you can do that.
I'm excited to share that with you.
Uh, thank you everybody who was here live.
Had a really great time chatting
with you, learning from you,
answering your questions, and would
love to see you again tomorrow
Thank you, everybody